<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cambridge, July 6, 1638 a generall bill of all those which have been buried in the 14 parishes of Cambridge, and the liberties of the same, from the 17 of May untill this present 6 of July, 1638.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1638</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A17735</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 4472.3</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S2541</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">24292936</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 24292936</idno>
            <idno type="VID">27498</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A17735)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 27498)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1849:10)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Cambridge, July 6, 1638 a generall bill of all those which have been buried in the 14 parishes of Cambridge, and the liberties of the same, from the 17 of May untill this present 6 of July, 1638.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 broadside.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Cambridge, England :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1638]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the University of Cambridge. Archives.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Cambridge (England) --  Statistics, Vital.</term>
               <term>Cambridge (England) --  History.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="bill_of_mortality">
            <pb facs="tcp:27498:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>Cambridge, <date>July 6. 1638.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <head>¶ A generall bill of all thoſe which have been buried in the 14 pariſhes of <hi>Cambridge,</hi> and the liberties of the ſame, from the 17 of <hi>May</hi> un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>till this preſent 6 of <hi>July,</hi> 1638.</head>
            <p>THat the number of all thoſe which are dead of the plague, or other diſeaſes in <hi>Cambridge,</hi> and the 14 pariſhes of the ſame, may be truly known, (after due examination of the Church-wardens and Clerks of the ſeverall pariſhes) we have thought fit to publiſh this bill, wherein is truly ſet down the number of all thoſe perſons which have died in any of the pariſhes in <hi>Cambridge,</hi> or at the peſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>houſe, and of what diſeaſes, ſince the 17 day of <hi>May,</hi> untill the 6 of <hi>July,</hi> being full ſeven weeks, and before any infection of the plague, or ſuſpicion of the ſame was perceived in <hi>Cambridge.</hi> Hereafter we intend every fortnight to publiſh the like bills, that thereby all ſuch as deſire, may be truly inform<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed from time to time how the ſickneſſe increaſeth or decreaſeth with us.</p>
            <p>All the Colledges (God be praiſed) are, and have continued without any infection of the plague, except <hi>Jeſus</hi> Colledge, where onely one died of the plague the 12 of <hi>June.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell role="label"> </cell>
                     <cell role="label">bur.</cell>
                     <cell role="label">pl.</cell>
                     <cell role="label">day and diſeaſe.</cell>
                     <cell role="label"> </cell>
                     <cell role="label"> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell rows="2">All-hallows</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">13</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">13</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>May</hi> 25. <hi>June</hi> 6, 14, 16, 19, 23, 24, 25, 30. <hi>July</hi> 1.</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">13</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>At the peſt-houſe, of the ſame pariſh, <hi>June</hi> 29, 30. <hi>July</hi> 5.</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell rows="7">S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Andrews <hi>Cambr.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell rows="7">9</cell>
                     <cell rows="7">0</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>May</hi> 19. child-bed</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell rows="7">9</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>May</hi> 21. &amp; <hi>June</hi> 14. in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fants</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>May</hi> 28. Kings-evil</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 2. aged <add>infant</add>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 7, &amp; 23. conſum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ption</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 13. ſmall pox</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 21. meaſels</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Andrews <hi>Barnwel</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 28. aged and bed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rid</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell rows="2">S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Benedicts</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">3</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">0</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>May</hi> 22, &amp; <hi>July</hi> 2. con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumption</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">3</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 17. convulſion</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell rows="4">S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Butolphs</cell>
                     <cell rows="4">6</cell>
                     <cell rows="4">0</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>May</hi> 25. fever</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell rows="4">6</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 11, 19. conſum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ption</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 13. infant</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>July</hi> 5. meaſels</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell rows="2">S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Clements</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">2</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">2</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 25. ſuſpected of the plague</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>July</hi> 4. at the peſt-houſe</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell rows="2">S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Edwards</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">4</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">0</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>May</hi> 17. <hi>June</hi> 13, 19. infants</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">4</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 21. fever</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell rows="2">S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Giles</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">2</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">0</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>May</hi> 22. conſumption</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 15. infant</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell rows="3">S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Maries <hi>the great</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell rows="3">5</cell>
                     <cell rows="3">0</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>May</hi> 19. <hi>June</hi> 24, &amp; 28, conſumption</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell rows="3">5</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 29. grief</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>July</hi> 1. riſing of the lights</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Maries <hi>the leſſe</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 19. conſumption</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell rows="2">S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Michaels</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">2</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">0</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>May</hi> 21. meaſels</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell rows="2">2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>May</hi> 29. winde-co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Peters</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 29. aged</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Sepulchres</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 16. conſumption</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell rows="4">Trinitie</cell>
                     <cell rows="4">4</cell>
                     <cell rows="4">0</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>May</hi> 21. dropſie</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell rows="4">4</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 11. rickets</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>June</hi> 21. meaſels</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>July</hi> 4. conſumption</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>The totall number of all the burialls from <hi>May</hi> 17 untill this preſent <hi>July</hi> 6</cell>
                     <cell>55.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Whereof of the plague</cell>
                     <cell>16.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Pariſhes infected and ſuſpected</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Pariſhes cleare</cell>
                     <cell>12.</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Ra. Brownrigg,</hi> Vicechancellour.</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Chr. Roſe,</hi> Maior.</item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
            <pb facs="tcp:27498:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
